<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Statements on Ramium</title>
    <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/tags/personal-statements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Statements on Ramium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/tags/personal-statements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Templates</title>
      <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/email_tempalte/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/email_tempalte/</guid>
      <description>Thank you COVID19 Lockdown March, 2020 Members of the Biostatistics Department, On March 9, I left my office in Building 2 of the Harvard Chan School, ready to get away for a few days during my son Adam&#39;s spring break. COVID-19 was something we were already worrying about and our department had been proactive in preparing to offer classes and to conduct thesis exams over Zoom. I was sure that whatever we were facing, we would deal with it quickly, and that before long things would be back to normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Templates</title>
      <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/email_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/email_templates/</guid>
      <description>Thank you  COVID19 Lockdown March, 2020   Holidays  Christmas Thanksgiving  JQ 2020     Voting  2020 Presidential Election  JQ Election Day JQ Post Election Post-Election uncertainty      Thank you COVID19 Lockdown March, 2020 Members of the Biostatistics Department, On March 9, I left my office in Building 2 of the Harvard Chan School, ready to get away for a few days during my son Adam&#39;s spring break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT-HMS Innovation Interview</title>
      <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/mit-hms_innovationinterview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/mit-hms_innovationinterview/</guid>
      <description>A passion for healthcare. Tell us why you are passionate about healthcare After I graduated from college with a computer science degree, my first job was as research contractor for Pfizer Computational Science division. At that time, I worked with the research team to develop software to perform in silico small molecule screening. It was my first revelation that data mining and modeling can drastically excellerate drug discovery process that not only save money for the company and save time from development to market of the patients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>