<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on Ananke</title>
    <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/categories/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on Ananke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yaoyu Final Email to QBRC and JQ team</title>
      <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/email_20200724/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/email_20200724/</guid>
      <description>Dear all,
As Angela Merkel said in the Harvard commencement last year: &amp;ldquo;Time and time again, we need to be prepared to keep bring things to an end in order to feel the magic of new beginnings.&amp;rdquo; And after a fantastic decade run along with you, it is my time to bid adieu today and to seek a new beginning.
Unfortunately we can&amp;rsquo;t have one for the road as current colleagues, yet, as many great things in life, what matters is the journey itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/quotes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#34;There areonly two kinds of theories: those that are wrong and those that are incomplete.&amp;#34; &amp;ndash; Karl Popper
&amp;#34;We look for medicine to be an orderly field of knowledge and procedure. But it is not. It is an imperfect science, an enterprise of constantly changing knowledge, uncertain information, fallible individuals, and at the same time lives on the line&amp;#34; &amp;ndash;Atul Gawande, Complications: A Surgeon&amp;rsquo;s Notes on an Imperfect Science, 2003</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[English] Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/hugothemecreationtutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 15:43:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yaoyu-e-wang.github.io/posts/hugothemecreationtutorial/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
